Episode 10                   Birthday
Pardon the intrusion...
So, this is Rin's house...
Let me give you the tour.
Here's the living room.
Here's the bathroom.
And here we've got the
traditional Japanese room.
I'm really starting to enjoy this!
So am I!
Come to think of it, Rin,
you still talk pretty formally around me...
Don't you figure it's time to stop?
Y-Yeah...
Granted, it's kinda late at this point.
'Sup!
Uh... What do you mean, 'sup?
I'm just... so happy right now...
I'll do better once I get used to it!
Want me to think up
a penalty game to motivate you?
And I have to ask... will this
tour include your room?
It will not.
But I want more details!
Senpai, you have a real knack
for dressing dishes.
Er, I mean, you're real good!
Wait, were you being formal just now?
What are you talking about?
Seriously...?
There!
You really are good at this!
Well, we made it together,
so I had to pull my weight somehow.
Kinda like... being a husband...
Playing a husband, I mean... acting.
Y'know, like a role.
I'll do my best
in the role of the wife, too.
Which kind of sauce do you prefer,
Japanese or western style?
I really can't decide!
Let's make both then! Think we can manage?
We don't have a lot ingredients,
so it'll just have to be western today.
We can do Japanese some other time.
'Kay...
I wanna do that too.
You want a taste, huh?
Of the latest recipe
from head chef Imp-chan?!
Imp-chan being able to cook would be
an interesting contrast...
And if it was Cool-chan,
would it taste differently?!
Food's getting cold.
As long as you don't!
Is there a festival going on nearby?
Yep. It's not big, but they have fireworks.
Wanna go?
Nah.
I'd rather stay here,
now that I'm finally at your place.
But I want Senpai
to see me wearing a yukata...
Come on! Don't try to tempt me like that.
It's gonna make me wanna go!
Come on, Senpai! Let's watch the fireworks.
Are we going?
Just come on.
Your room?
Yeah.
The fireworks are visible from my window.
Um... not gonna... turn the lights on?
The fireworks should be starting soon.
Let's leave them off until then.
It being dark won't let me
snoop around in here, though.
There you go, ruining the mood...
I mean, come on... I'm still
a rowdy little fella, deep down.
I'm looking forward to the fireworks.
Yeah. Me too.
What?! Did your parents come home?!
They shouldn't have!
I'm incoming with some spoils from the festival
It was just Megu...
That scared me...
But shouldn't you answer the door?
I want to watch the fireworks too,
but I'd feel bad about
pretending no one was home.
I was planning to do
that during the fireworks...
Good job with the delivery.
I never should've told you
about the job I got...
But you're earning good money off us.
Thanks for doing business with us!
You didn't eat our fries, did you?
Y'know, I really should have!
You wanna come in and take a break?
This is a good time to stay busy, though...
You realize we haven't
done anything fun lately
because you're so hard
to get hold of, right?
I'm trying to save up, man!
Isn't being able to set your own hours the
whole point of these online
food delivery services?!
Wow, settle down.
I wanna go camping!
Camping? Sounds expensive.
Isn't that what you're saving up for?
Don't be dumb.
Camping's so awesome, though.
Fishing, barbecuing...
It's bound to be the most
memorable event of the summer!
Not the most memorable, no.
Oh, Nanakura-san, right?
Not necessarily...
Dammit, you did something, didn't you?!
I wanna ask about it! But I don't wanna hear
about it! But I wanna know!
Seriously, it's not a big deal.
Dammit, running your mouth about
how stupidly happy you are...
I didn't even say anything.
Then what are you saving up for?
Well, her birthday's coming... up...
I want you to deliver me
some ice cream. Now!
Don't make it sound like I'm your gopher!
Unacceptable.
You being the only one
fully enjoying summer...
Die
I guess we better go
on that camping trip, huh?
No! No more camping.
Instead, we're going to
play tag at the local park.
That's one heck of a downgrade!
You're gonna be doing this
for the rest of the day...
That sounds like hell.
I'm gonna make sure you have
the worst summer ever!
Knock it off!
I'm gonna get back to work then.
I won't let you escape!
Senpai's clothes!
Whatcha doing?
N-Nothing!
Oh, this jacket wanted me to wear it, so...
Say what?!
Missy, you mean to tell me you can hear
the voice of these clothes?
This has turned into a thing...
Long ago, all the folks around these parts
could hear the voices of clothing.
They say hearing the voice
of clothing brings good fortune,
and man and clothing had
a well-worn symbiotic relationship.
Was that a pun?
But one day, a different type
of clothing came from across the sea...
And ever since, we haven't been able to
hear the voice of the clothing.
These foreign words
are impossible to figure out...
Are we talking about language?
Wow.
And that wraps up my reports
for summer vacation!
Except I'm lying. Look at how
much I have left to do...
You'll need to hurry
if you want to finish at all.
I wanted at least a taste of being done...
Want to take a break?
If you were the same grade as me,
you could help me out...
Treat me to lunch at the cafeteria
three times and I'll do it!
You can act like we have the same classes
but that won't actually get the reports done...
I work and I work but it never ends.
Come to think of it,
what are you guys putting
on for the culture festival?
Let's see...
It's about two people who look identical,
but have opposite personalities.
They switch places
and go to each other's schools...
Here's the script.
That's a lot of doodles!
Preferences: Tsundere-chan: Lemon tea, bunnies, friends, anime.
Characteristic actions: Crossing arms, Trying to look taller.
Gets embarrassed.
Imp-chan: Teasing, black earrings? Gum.
Maybe cooking for contrast?
Smirking, biting lower lip, body contact .
Spoiled-chan: Teasing Selfies. Likes to talk, likes conversations.
Looking upwards from below. Talking in a sweet voice.
Poking with fingers.
Preferences... Tsundere-chan...
lemon tea... bunnies...
What's this?
I was thinking about profiles and such...
and I wrote some notes.
So, Tsundere-chan likes bunnies?
Yes...
Oh, the ones with the droopy ears, right?!
Enough already!
Aw, it's fine!
Give it back!
You even came up with habits...
What is it?
I really don't deserve to have
all these nice girls be into me.
Make them all happy, okay?
You're too close. I can't relax like this.
Rin, you wanna have some watermelon?
Are you sure we can finish it?
Well, it's already cut and everything.
Plus, you can eat the rind,
and the seeds are chocolate.
You're talking about ice cream, aren't you?
Remember what I said about getting a taste?
What should I get Rin for her birthday?
Gifts... search.
Craft beer?!
Probably should include some snacks, then.
Come to think of it, her script had
a bunch of preferences in it...
If I remember right, it was bunnies?
Is that a problem?!
Oh, this is perfect!
Aim Higher
And Spoiled-chan would
want something cute...
I want something cute!
I could get two!
As for Cool-chan...
A late-summer gift?
Thank you.
Uh, no, it's a birthday present...
Maybe no Japanese sweets.
That just leaves Imp-chan...
But it's Rin's birthday, right?
Would she like it if I
picked out a serious gift?
Although that's kind of embarrassing...
Pseudo Harem
Sorry about the wait! Let's go.
You're looking prettier lately, Rin.
What? Where did this come from?
I feel like you're looking nicer
since you got back from summer break.
Really? Oh, but I hadn't noticed!
I must've been imagining it...
Hey!
What do you think, Kiri-chan?
Give us the kouhai's opinion.
My opinion?
I was thinking she seemed different, too...
Not that she didn't look
pretty before, mind you!
Senpai, you're always lovely.
How earnest you are makes you
the cutest, Kiri-chan.
Seriously.
No, no, no...
Actually, did something
happen during summer vacation?
Oh, kitten, I think you might not
be old enough for this kind of talk!
You've definitely gotten funnier
since summer vacation, Rin!
Scary...
Rin, are you serious about running
in that getup this year?
Everyone has to cross-dress, right?
Looks hard to get around in...
These soles are really thick too!
I feel like drama puts too much effort
into the performance side
of things every year.
You don't even care about winning!
As long as you're rooting for me,
baby, I'm gonna be number one.
Yeah, I'm not really into Hotshot-kun.
A hotshot like me, rejected?!
Interesting...
Nanakura-senpai... sorry about the wait.
Kiri-chan!
I love you.
Squeeze
That's a pretty huge
difference in reactions!
M-Megu-senpai?! Is something wrong?
I really don't think a delicate young
boy would say something like that!
I've never seen Megu this excited before...
If it's for you, Nee-san, I don't mind
running until my body falls apart...
I get the feeling if I stay too
close by, I could taint him...
That's intense.
I wish I could've dressed like that.
It seems easier to run in.
I'm pretty confident in my running,
so you can count on me!
But Delicate-kyun's too delicate to run.
It's okay, I'll teach you all about it...
We will now begin our final event,
the inter-club, mixed-gender,
costume relay race!
On your marks...
Get set...
Yeah, go for it!
You've got this!
Come on!
Good luck, Senpai.
It's all yours!
Right!
These are in the way!
Senpai!
She's so cool!
Kiri-chan!
Show these people what
the drama club is made of!
Delicate-kyun can't run.
He's too fragile...
fragile...fragile... fragile...
That might be what helps
me figure out roles...
figure out roles...
Roles...roles...
The baton is now in the hands
of the drama club's anchor.
Oh, what's this?! She seems
unsteady on her feet!
Was it a good idea
for her to run in the race?
Oh, and they pass her one by one!
This is hard to watch...
It's okay! Just stop!
You don't have to run anymore!
Kiri-chan!
And now she's collapsed!
I'm not sure why, but something
about the sight of it is beautiful!
Are you okay, Kiri-chan?!
What did you think of my Delicate-kun?
Very good!
Come on, Kiri-chan!
I never thought you'd get me
something like this, Senpai...
I tried picking something
out... seriously...
Thank you!
I'll always cherish it!
I'm honestly surprised you went
with such a serious present.
Do you have to be surprised?
Then again, if you're that happy,
maybe the earnest approach isn't so bad.
Next, I want a present full of love too.
Spoiled-chan...
I don't think I can do that.
I've got my heart set
on one girl, right now.
I was rejected...?
For some reason this is
a bigger shock than I thought.
I'm not gonna make eyes
at you or Imp-chan anymore!
No, no, no, don't do that!
I can't deal with that! There's just no way!
You really feel that strongly...?
Documentary: Much Ado About Nothing X
Documentary: Much Ado About Nothing X!
The drama circle found
itself desperate for time,
preparing for an upcoming performance...
The production of certain props
for the show are behind schedule!
Did you catch that?!
Yes, it's his fault!
I'm making soapboxes, which
the actors will be standing on.
I can't afford them getting hurt,
so I have to do a good job.
This man...
Just take a look at him.
See what I mean about doing a good job?
Considering the weight.